Andrew Cotter

Design & Computation

Contact

thatcotter.github.io cotter.andrew.p@gmail.com 267-614-3716

Personal statement

I'm a constant learner. Each project is an opportunity towards discoverying new tools and processes, as well as cultivating new a better understanding of technology, and our relationship to it. I like to make things that have both physical and digital dimensions to them. In my work, I try to manifest the convergence of these two fields in the form of interactive installations, games, and wearable devices.

I'm always looking at our relationships to technology and the ways we wield it: how it does things for us, and to us.

Core Competencies & Disciplines



Design Research

The first step to solving a problem is understanding it. By interviewing steakholders and testing prototypes, I can better undertand what the solution is.



User Experience

I'm focused on making products centered around the people that will use them, making their interaciton as intuitive as possible.



Poetic Computation

I approach code like creative writing-focusing on the mechanics, the demystification of tools, and hacking the conventions of art-making with computation.

Experience

Design/Development Intern, Cipher Prime Fall 2015 - Summer 2016

Assisting with design and development of video games and interactive media in various frameworks such as Unity, oF, and P5.js.

Interaction Developer, Night Kitchen Fall 2014 - Summer 2016

Leading design/development research by exploring new tools for the web and interactive installations and demonstrating implementations to the rest of the team.

Lead Technoloy Instructor, Lavner! Camps Summer 2014

Taught campers to make interactive game experiences with Clickteam Fusion, simple robotics with Lego Mindstorms, and architectural principles with Minecraft.

Design Intern, PostGreen Homes Summer 2013

Designed and modeled bathroom and kitchen cabinetry in Rhino to be CNC'd and put into production.

Skills

Adobe Suite

Photoshop Illustrator InDesign

Code / Web

Processing openFrameworks Unity Arduino HTML/CSS

javaScript/p5js 3D Modeling

Cinema 4D Rhino SketchUp

Analog

Sketching Woodshop Tools



Education & Honors

MFA Design & Technology Parsons, Class of 2018

President of D+T Dorkshops (2016-2017)

BS Industrial Design University of the Arts, Class of 2014

3.0 GPA President of UArts Literary Society (2012-2014) Teaching Assistant for Design Semantics (2014)

Achieved the rank of Eagle Scout BSA Troop 139, 2010